Harold G. Simms Papers MS046
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Harold G. Simms Papers
1945 -- 1949
1900 -- 2015
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Simms, Harold G.
MS046
3.9 Linear Feet 3 record cartons, 2 album and scrapbook boxes, 1 flat file publications box
3 Digital Object(s)
3.19 Megabytes
This collection contains photographic materials, Tufts memorabilia, and WWII memorabilia created by or belonging to Harold G. Simms, who graduated from Tufts in 1949 and founded the Camera Club.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Harold G. Simms, 2007-2016, accession numbers MS-2017-031; 2013.035; 2010.016; 2009.032; 2007.024.
Arrangement
This collection is organized in six series: Slides and negatives of Tufts campus buildings; Slides of Tufts Mayoralty Parade; Tufts Camera Club; Memorabilia; WWII materials; and WWII born digital files.
Biographical / Historical
Harold Glenn Simms was born in 1926 to William E. Simms and Ruby Simms. William and his brother Eric J. Simms ran the Simms Bros Yacht Yard in Dorchester. In the 1940s, Harold supervised construction of boats, including T-boats, which the Army commissioned as passenger-cargo boats doubling as harbor tugs (known as tug-transports, or T-boats during World War II). Pfc Harold G. Simms, 330th Infantry, E Company HQ, served in World War II and was awarded a Purple Heart, and later on received a Bronze Star for 'outstanding devotion to duty as a company runner during military operations from July 4 1944 to May 8 1945 in France, Luxembourg, Belgium and Germany.' Harold Simms later attended Tufts University (1946-1949) and graduated in 1949 with a B.S. in Civil Engineering, cum laude. While at Tufts, Simms founded the Camera Club (1947) and served as its president (1947/48) and treasurer (1948/49). After graduating, Simms worked as naval architect.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographic slides, Tufts memorabilia, and WWII memorabilia. Slides were taken by Harold G. Simms between 1946 and 1949 and consist of 36 color slides of campus landscapes and 35 color slides of Mayoralty Parades in 1947 and 1948. The collection also includes photographic negatives, information on the Tufts Camera Club, Tufts memorabilia, and WWII-related materials.
Tufts Camera Club; Tufts Mayoralty Parade; Tufts Campus Buildings; World War, 1939-1945; Alumni collections; University history; World War II
- Slides and negatives of Tufts campus buildings, 1945 -- 1949; MS046.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series includes 36 color slides taken by Harold G. Simms of Tufts University campus. Also includes negatives of campus buildings and landscapes.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by subject.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Tufts Campus and Buildings, 1946 -- 1949; MS046.001.001.00001 (Box MS046 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Campus and Buildings, 1946 -- 1949; MS046.001.001.00002 (Box MS046 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Campus and Buildings, 1946 -- 1949; MS046.001.001.00003 (Box MS046 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and landscape negatives, 1945 -- 1949; MS046.001.002.00001 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
- Slides of Tufts Mayoralty Parade, 1947 -- 1948; MS046.002; 0.25 Linear Feet; 1 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains 32 color slides of the Mayoralty Parade at Tufts.
  - Slides of Tufts Mayoralty Parade, 1947 -- 1948; MS046.002.001.00001 (Box MS046 Shared 1)
  - Slides of Tufts Mayoralty Parade, 1947; MS046.002.001.00002 (Box MS046 Shared 1)
    - Students on a red truck during Tufts mayoralty parade, 1947; MS046.002.001.00002.00001; Simms, Harold G. (Box MS046 Shared 1)
      Medford Campus; Mayoralty; Trucks; Parade floats; slide (photograph)
- Tufts Camera Club, 1945 -- 1949; MS046.003; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains membership lists and clippings related to the Tufts Camera Club.
  This series is arranged in original order.
  - Tufts Camera Club, 1947 -- 1949; MS046.003.002.00002 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - Camera Club prints, 1945 -- 1949; MS046.003.002.00009 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
- Memorabilia, 1900 -- 1949; MS046.004; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains memorabilia and clippings related to Simms' time at Tufts including information on civil engineering and commencement.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Civil engineering clippings, 1948 -- 1949; MS046.004.002.00004 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - Tufts Yacht Club Dance Program, 1902 -- 1949; MS046.004.002.00005 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - Commencement program, 1906 -- 1949; MS046.004.002.00006 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - Ivy Society date books, 1946 -- 1949; MS046.004.002.00007 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - Tufts Bulletin, 1949; MS046.004.002.00008 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Ballou Hall, Tufts College, Mass., 1907 -- 1917; MS046.004.002.00009 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
    picture postcards
  - [Postcard] Museum, Tufts College, Medford, Mass., 1910; MS046.004.002.00010 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Barnum Museum, Tufts College, 1900 -- 1910; MS046.004.002.00011 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Barnum Museum, Tufts College, Mass, 1909; MS046.004.002.00012 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] College Buildings, View from Mystic Reservoir, Tufts College, Mass, 1907 -- 1917; MS046.004.002.00013 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Goddard Chapel, Tufts College, Mass, 1908; MS046.004.002.00014 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Goddard Chapel, Tufts College, Mass, 1941; MS046.004.002.00015 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Goddard Chapel, Tufts College, Mass, 1907 -- 1914; MS046.004.002.00016 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] College Avenue, Tufts College, Medford, Mass, 1912; MS046.004.002.00017 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
  - [Postcard] Professors Row, Tufts College. Mass., 1900 -- 1920; MS046.004.002.00018 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
    Women standing in front of homes on Professor's Row.
  - [Postcard] Professors Row, Tufts College. Mass., 1927; MS046.004.002.00019 (Box MS046 Shared 2)
- World War II materials, 1943 -- 2015; 1943 -- 1951; MS046.005; 2.5 Linear Feet
  This series documents Simms' WWII service and is composed of two photo albums, negatives, a scrapbook, loose newspapers, letters to his family, a bound autobiographical volume, and various memorabilia such as tickets, postcards, etc.
  This series is arranged by format.
  - Correspondence, 1943 -- 1945; MS046.005.003.000001 (Box data_value_missing_067115ea436e10896ce526755c16129c, Folder 1-17, Box 1)
  - Negatives, circa 1940s; MS046.005.003.000002 (Box data_value_missing_067115ea436e10896ce526755c16129c, Folder 18-19, Box 2)
  - Chronicle of a World War II Army Bugler, 2015; MS046.005.003.000003 (Box data_value_missing_067115ea436e10896ce526755c16129c, Folder 20, Box 3)
  - Memorabilia, circa 1940 -- 1951; MS046.005.004 (Box data_value_missing_067115ea436e10896ce526755c16129c, Box 4)
  - Photograph album, circa 1942 -- 1945; MS046.005.005 (Box 5-7; 2-6)
  - Army publications, circa 1940s -- 1950s; MS046.005.006.000001 (Box 5-7; 2-6, Folder 1-2)
  - Photograph album, circa 1940s; MS046.005.006.000002 (Box 5-7; 2-6)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1942 -- 1945; MS046.005.007 (Box 5-7; 2-6)
    Physical condition: use of scrapbook requires supervision of archivist.
- World War II born digital files, circa 2015; MS046.006; 3.19 Megabytes; 3 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains trancriptions of Simms' WWII letters, as well as information about people and places in his WWII photograph albums in the form of narrative captions.
  Simms wrote a letter to his parents nearly every day between 1943 and 1945. His letters are conversational in tone and discuss the everyday realities of army life. They include discussion of interaction with fellow servicemen; daily activities; accommodations and food; weather, sights, and civilians in cities in France, Belgium, and Germany, where Simms was stationed; as well as Simms's observations about the war.
  Photograph albums depict basic training at Camp Croft in Spartanburg, North Carolina, as well as buildings, civilians, and scenes of army life in various cities in France, Belgium, and Germany.
  Materials are arranged in original order.
  - Army Letters, Overseas, Updated, 2016-08-04; MS046.006.00001; 1 Digital Object(s); 2.61 Megabytes
    Transcribed WWII letters and list of correspondents.
  - Army letters, U.S.A v. 3, 2016-08-04; MS046.006.00002; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.37 Megabytes
    Transcribed WWII letters.
  - #01 List of Photographs Updated #3, 2016-08-04; MS046.006.00003; 1 Digital Object(s); 0.21 Megabytes
    List of narrative captions for photograph albums.